Guide to the J. B. S. (Jacob Benjamin Salutsky) Hardman Papers TAM.050
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Writings, 1910-1970
  - Political Trends in American Labor, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Political Weight of Unionism, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - The Position of the Progressive, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Postscripts to UAW Profile, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Power Personnel (part III), undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Power Accumulation, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Power of the Grassroots, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - The President's Engagements (on Tom Mooney), undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Published Works, 1952-1969 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Processing Labor Unity (published), undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Profile (part I), undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Profile (part III), undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Profile (part III), undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Pyramid of Union Leadership, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Questions Regarding W.F.T.U., undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Quotes, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Quotes, Mar 7, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Rackets, Ethics, and Beyond, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Radical Interludes, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Radical Labor Movement, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Radicalism, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Rebel Generations, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Red Fears in White Hearts: A Review, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Report of Discrimination against Negro Girls of ACWA by YMHA of Elizabeth, NJ, by Beth Cunningham, Jun 13, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Report on Inter-Union Conference, May 1950 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Religion of Labor, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Rendezvous With Destiny, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Committee on Future Friends in the Labor Movement, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Walter Reuther: Notes and Drafts, 1950s (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Walter Reuther: Typescripts and Published Article ( Labor and Nation, 1958), undated, May 1958 (Box 26, Folder 10a)
  - Revolutionary Syndicalism (in Russian), Apr 1909 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Round Table in Heaven, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Report on Labor Trends and Trouble in 1945 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Research, undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - If Revolution, If Fascism, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Revolutionary Inventory, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Revolutionary Who is Afraid, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Roosevelt Revolution, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Seeking the Square of the Circle in the Current Labor Picture, 1944 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Seminar on Labor, Apr 6, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Sense of the Whole, Jan 1953-Feb 1953 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Set of Beliefs, Jul 17, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Social Power (notes), undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Socialism and Democracy are Incompatible, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Socialist Party, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Somewhere in America (Shreds and Patches), undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Soviet America: A Communist Way Out, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Square of the Circle (notes), undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Staff Inventories (inventory material), undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Stakes of Leadership, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - State of the Unions, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Summary of "Labor Examines Itself", undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Synopsis of Norman Thomas's Speech to the Socialist Party Convention, May 23, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Synoptic Notes, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - A Table for Two and Communism (CIO-published), undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Technocracy or Power, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Term Paper2: Guidelines for Students, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - 1932 in Retrospect: Third Year of Depression, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - The Tragedy of Radical Labor Leadership, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Trafficking in Revolution, 1930 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Thunder on the Left-Interpretations, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - ULPC and the Metaphysics of Unity (published), undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Union Democracy in Crisis, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Union Democracy-I.R.R.A., May 2, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Union Elite, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Union Folklore and Reality, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Union Leadership and Internal Democracy (published), Feb 1955 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Union Power (notes), undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Union Problems in Profile, undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Union Growth: Facts and Potentialities, undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Union Leaders, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Unionism (drafts and articles), undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Unionism in total, 1956, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Unions in Democratic America, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - United and/or Inclusive Unionism, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - United Front, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - United Labor Policy Committee (published), undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - United Steelworkers of America, CIO, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Unity That is Now Possible, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - An Un-Mailed Letter to Walter P. Reuther, Labor and Nation, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Wanted: A Triumvirate, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Web of Union Government (workset), undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - What Ails Labor?, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - What Is the Matter with American Labor?, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - What Labor Is 'Up To', undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - What Makes Labor Tick?, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - What Reuther Said, and Didn't Say, Apr 20, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - What Trade Unionists Seem to Want, undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Where the Battle of Our Generation Lives and Will be Fought, undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Which Way Labor?, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - White-Collar Labor, Nov 21, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Why American Labor Behaves Like That, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Will Labor Fight?", Dec 29, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Wings in Needledom, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Worker Political Action (lecture), Jun 23, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Workers Education, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Timeline: Roosevelt Administration, 1933-1943, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - The Young Lassalle (B. C. Vladeck) (in Yiddish), undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Zygielbojm, Szmul, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Drafts, Syllabi, etc., undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Reviews of J. B. S. Hardman's Work, 1928-1929 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Yiddish Articles by Hardman, 1910-1965 (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Series V: Labor and Political Activities, 1923-1967
  This series includes records of the Inter-Union Institute for Labor and Democracy (1942-1953), incomplete committee minutes and copies of papers presented at the Columbia University Seminars on Labor (1948-1967), and material relating to the Hardman's expulsion from the Workers Party of America in 1923, his involvement in the American Workers Party in the mid-1930s, records of the Conference for Progressive Labor Action, a survey on attitudes of labor leaders done for Elmo Roper and Louis Harris by Hardman in 1950, and material on Hanna Goldstein Hardman's studies at the New York School of Philanthropy and her work on immigrants.
  - Letter to a Confused Liberal, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Mature Collective Bargaining: Prospects and Problems, Institute of Industrial Relations, University of California, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Testimony: "Communist Domination of Certain Unions": Senate Committee on Labor and Welfare, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Codetermination: Labor's Middle Way in Germany, foreword by Hardman, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Address to Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, NYC, Jan 7, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Union Profiles (typescripts by various authors): IAM, Teamsters, Needle Trades, IATSE (by Roy Brewer), undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1948-1949 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor (statements), 1949 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1949-1950 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1950-1951 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1951-1952 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1953-1954 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1954-1955 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1954-1955 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1955-1956 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1956-1957 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1957-1958 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1959-1960 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 196-1961 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1961-1962 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1962-1963 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor (Jobs-Employment), 1963-1964 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Labor, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University Research, 1957-1964 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1942-1944 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Inter-Union Institute: Conference on Labor and its Position, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Inter-Union Institute, Proceedings of Meetings, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1948 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1950-1953 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Inter-Union Institute, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Inter-Union Institute: Finance Reports, 1946-1960 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Inter-Union Institute: Legal/Tax Matters, undated (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Labor and Nation, undated (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Labor Theory: Commentaries on Perlman Theory, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Labor Theory: National Conference of Labor Educators, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Labor Theory: Perlman, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Labor Theory: Saposs and Carey Typescripts, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Labor Theory, Mar 13, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Labor Theory, Articles on, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Labor Theory, Articles on, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Labor Theory, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - American Workers Party, 1933-1934 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - American Workers Party: Clippings, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Workers Party of America, Hardman's Expulsion from, 1923 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Conference for Progressive Labor Action (printed items), undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Conference for Progressive Labor Action: Correspondence, 1929 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Conference for Progressive Labor Action: National Executive Committee Minutes, 1929-1933 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - United Conference for Progressive Political Action, 1938 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Jan 1949-Mar 1949 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Apr 1949-Jun 1949 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Jul 1949-Sep 1949 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Oct 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Jan 1950-Mar 1950 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Apr 1950-Jun 1950 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Jul 1950-Sep 1950 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Oct 1950-Dec 1950 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Jan 1951-Jun 1951 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Jul 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (CBS Radio), Jan 1952-Jun 1952 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (NBC Radio), Jul 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (NBC Radio), Jan 1953-Mar 1953 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (NBC Radio), Apr 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (NBC Radio), Jul 1953-Sep 1953 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (NBC Radio), Oct 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Elmo Roper's Papers (NBC Radio), Jan 1954 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Roper: L. Harris Questionnaire, 1950-1951 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Roper: L. Harris Questionnaire-Raw Results, 1950-1951 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - L. Harris Labor Leadership Studies, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - The Private Thinking on Public Issues, Louis Harris, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Labor Examines Itself, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Allen, Walter M., "A Survey of the Extent of Unionizing of Daily Newspaper Pressrooms", undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Bailer, Lloyd H., "Non-White Color Line", undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Barbash, Jack, "Communist Unionism-Aims and Means", undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Barbash, Jack, "The Elements of Industrial Relations", Jan 14, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Barbash, Jack, "Industrialism and Women's Status", undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Barbash, Jack, "The ILGWU as an Organization in the Age of Dubinsky", Jul 12, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Barbash, Jack, "John R. Commons and the Americanization of the Labor Problem", Dec 1966 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Barbash, Jack, "The Labor Movement in the Changing Industrial Order", Aug 24, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Barbash, Jack, "Labor and the Common Market", Nov 10, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Barbash, Jack, "The Practice of Union Democracy", Feb 26, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Barbash, Jack, "The Present Status and Future Course of the American Labor Movement", Oct 18, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Barbash, Jack, "Rationalization in the Union", undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Barbash, Jack, "Steel Unionism", undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Barbash, Jack, "Unions and Politics", Feb 20, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Barkin, Solomon, "Free Enterprise", undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Barkin, Solomon, "Operational Pattern of Textile Unionism", Jul 1954 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Bell, Daniel, "The Growth of American Unions", Dec 14, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Bell, Daniel, "Labor Profiles", Apr 8, 1953 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Bernstein, Irving, "Union Growth and Structural Cycles", undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Brewer, Roy H., "International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture of the U.S. and Canada, AFL", undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Cox, Archibald, "The Role of Law in Preserving Union Democracy", Apr 30, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Cunningham, Elizabeth, "Cultural Activities in Small Town New Jersey", undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - David, Henry, "From Speech of Hon. James J. Davis, AFL Convention", 1931 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Dunlop, John T., "The Public Interest in Internal Affairs of Unions", undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Elby, Kermit, "Democracy, How Many Crimes…?", undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Elby, Kermit, "The Expert in the Labor Movement", undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Elby, Kermit, "Why Labor Leaders are Lonesome", May 14, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Epstein, Albert, "The Union Dollar-In Profile", undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Hayes, A. J., "I.A.M.", undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Hedges, M. H., "Counter-Balance in Suburbia, USA", undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Lipset, Seymour M., "International Typographical Union", Jul 16, 1951 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Lipset, Seymour M., "The Law and Trade Union Democracy", 1960-1961 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Mayer, Martin P., "Cases in the State Courts", undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Mayer, Martin P., "Union Members' Rights and the Courts", undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Meyer, Arthur S., "Union Policy and Power in Collective Bargaining", undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Neufeld, Maurice F.; The Historical Relationships of Liberals and Intellectuals to Organized Labor in the U.S.", Nov 1963 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Mills, C. Wright, "The Intellectual and the Labor Leader", Apr 8, 1945 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Pearlman, Leo: Comments on Hardman Manuscript A(pamphlet in, undated (Box 43, Folder 5a)
  - Piore, Norma, "Communication Workers of America, C.I.O.", undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Plumb, Gleen E., "An Industrial Program", Jan 1, 1920 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Polakov, Walter N., "Engineering Service for the Labor Union", Feb 17, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Raskin, Abraham H., "The Labor-Industry Question: As Labor Sees It", Apr 15, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Reuther, Walter-Report of the President, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Rorty, James, "Camp Followers and Fellow Travelers", undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Samson, Leon, "Towards a United Front" (outline), undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Saposs, David J., "Rebirth of the American Labor Movement", Dec 28, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Seidman, Joel, "The Needle-Trades: Practical Idealism in the Labor Movement", undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Slichter, Sumner H., "The Position of Trade Unions in the American Economy", May 1, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Slichter, Sumner H., "Social and Economic Impact of the Pension Trend", Feb 13, 1950 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Shister, Joseph, "Power Patterns in a Local Labor Movement", undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Shister, Joseph, "Power Structure and Relationship in an Industrial Center (Buffalo, NY)", undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Strand, Axel, "Study Trip to the United States", undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Taft, Philip, "Opposition to Union Officers in Elections", Feb 1944 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Taft, Philip, "Reflections on the Present State of the Labor Movement", undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Taft, Philip, "Understanding Union Administration", undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Tenenbaum, Frank, "A Philosophy of Labor", undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Tippett, Tom, "The Illinois Miners", Feb 7, 1930 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Tyler, Gus, "A Political Theory of the Labor Movement", undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Warner, Aaron, "The Role of the Union in the Shop in Britain", 1955 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Wartenberg, George, "International Typographical Union", undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Wolman, Leo, and Gustav Peek, "The Changing Role of Labor and Labor Groups in our Social Structure", undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Wladka [early drafts of portions of the English translation of On Both Sides of the Wall by Vladka Meed?], undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Conferences Attended, undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Proceedings: New York State Industrial Union Council, Jun 19, 1942-Jun 20, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 14)
- Series VI: Clippings, undated
  This series contains clippings on subjects collected by Hardman.
  - Clippings: Intellectuals, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: Foreign Policy, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: Communism, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: Fascism, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: Eastern Europe, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Clippings: Economy, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Clippings: Conservationism, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Clippings: Corporations, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Collective Bargaining, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: The Black Problem, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: The Jewish Problem, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: Justice, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: Labor, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: Literature, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: Opposition to the USSR (within and outside), undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Clippings: Radicalism, undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Clippings: Religion, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Clippings: Socialism, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Sociology, undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: Leon Trotsky, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: Unions, undated (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: United Front, undated (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Clippings: The USA during the War, undated (Box 46, Folder 13)
- Series VII: Non-Print Materials, 1940s-1950s
  This series contains photographs of Hardman with other individuals and organizations at events, as well as a scrapbook from Hardman's testimonial dinner.
  - Group Photographs, Including Images of Hardman, Genis, Maurice Forge, and Robert P. Patterson, 1940s-1950s (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Group Portraits, Including Jewish Social Federation of America Convention, undated, 1951 (Box 47)
  - Norman Thomas 70th Anniversary Celebration Materials, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - "Political History of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers" Pages and Buttons, after 1942 (Box 47)
  - Portraits of Hardman, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Portrait of Unknown Woman, undated (Box 47)
  - Testimonial Dinner in honor of J.B.S. Hardman Scrapbook, 1942 (Box 48, Folder 1)